What city is this?
Who are you?
Is this not my own body?
Machines that can fly that freely through the sky?
Apparently, in this world,
mechanical technology
developed instead of alchemy.
That's why there are machines here
that we cannot comprehend.
"This world"?
Didn't you realize?
This place...
is the other side of the gate.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who obtain it are set free from the Law of Equivalent Exchange.
There is no need to pay a price
in order to obtain something, either.
We sought it and found it.
It sounds like something has happened at the Central Command Center.
There's a lot of confusion,
and I couldn't make out any details.
No matter.
We'll be able to hold out well enough against the ragtag soldiers
that Major General Hakuro
has scraped together, at least.
And as long as the Colonel realizes his dream during that period, everything will be fine.
Now that I think about it,
we've been fairly dumb, too.
We only vaguely know
what the Colonel is up to.
Lt. Colonel!
Reinforcements!
I'll go.
At this point, I'm not impersonating the Colonel anymore, right?
Something the matter?
No.
Was there something different that you wanted?
We won't tell your mother.
Come on,
I'll get you one more thing.
I'm sorry.
I saw you.
Is your treasure in there, Father?
I was going to give it to you when you were a little more grown up.
Really?
Hold on to this
for me until then.
I'm entrusting my life to you.
Be sure to guard it well.
Yes, sir, Your Excellency!
What's wrong?
The men outside said that
they saw someone suspicious!
Lieutenant Hawkeye, isn't it?
I'm honored that you remember me,
Your Excellency.
Around the front!
Move around to the front! Hurry!
Now!
Let's go.
But where to?
Our friends are planning to stage a wholesale uprising.
We're going there.
Bad news!
What's wrong?
Th-There was a communiqué...
The Führer's residence...
Your Excellency,
I'm on my way.
This world is filled with death.
They've even used a gas that takes
a great number of lives here in this world.
In the future, people will die
even more efficiently.
You saw it too, didn't you?
All of those lives,
spanning past to future,
become the source of our alchemy.
The source? What are you
talking about? Alchemy is...
Equivalent exchange?
But in order to return a broken radio
back to the way it was,
you need more than just
the same amount of mass.
You also need the energy it takes to reconstruct it.
You cannot have an equivalent exchange that ignores that.
The lives of those who die in this world
pass through the gate
and provide the energy for our alchemy. Is that what you're saying?
We all have a small gate, right here.
Alchemists open this gate,
and from there,
they connect to this world
and exploit those lives
to obtain power.
Then you are in league
with that woman after all!
No such thing as
equivalent exchange, huh?!
She said the same thing!
You've met Dante, have you?
I saw the love letter you sent her, too. The one from four hundred years ago!
You two have prolonged your lives by taking over other bodies!
Isn't that right?!
Why did you marry Mom?
Did you just want to see how fun it would be to have children like regular people do?
I loved her.
I loved your mom—Trisha.
It was the first time
I knew love.
You're lying!
Then why didn't you...?!
I didn't want you to see this decaying body.
Eat him.
Make him a complete Stone inside you.
Go on, snap to it.
Lust... What happened to Lust?
Lust! Lust!
What's the matter with you?! Eat him right now!
Let me see his son
gurgling away inside of you!
Dammit, I wanted to
tear the runt to pieces, too!
Lust...
Lust... Lust...
I'm sorry.
I know it was sudden.
Gluttony?
Be careful. Right now,
he possesses nothing but his appetite.
He was originally going to be the homunculus I used to refine red water.
He doesn't need a mind.
Dante cannot create a
Philosopher's Stone by herself.
That's why I always
kept myself in hiding.
But once I learned she had set her sights on you...
Were you sent through the gate by Dante too?
Dante separated my soul, mind, and body within the gate
and probably thinks
I am wandering around.
But I was able to
get through the gate.
What about this body?
This world differs from ours on the point of the development of alchemy
but is otherwise
almost identical to ours.
That's why there's a child here who is identical to you.
There's probably a boy out there
identical to Al too.
So that's why you were living next to this boy?
Your body is still
inside the gate.
Your soul and mind must be all that were drawn over
to dwell within
this Edward's body.
General Churchill said he needed to see you.
Hold on!
Open the gate within you.
Find your own body
within the gate.
You're coming back too,
aren't you?!
I cannot go back.
My body has already
passed through the gate.
I cannot use alchemy in this world.
But there's still time for you.
I'll come up with something!
I am going to die here,
in this body,
with the face and form
that Trisha loved.
I am relieved to know that
equivalent exchange is not true.
You don't necessarily need to pay a price
in order to obtain something.
When a parent loves their child, there can be no cost or reward.
Even so, if I stick with it,
I can still obtain something.
Anyone who makes an effort will be fairly rewarded.
If you pay the price, you can acquire an equal happiness.
That's the kind of equivalent exchange I'd like to believe in.
Reality...
Reality isn't like that.
So if you say it's a childish theory, then I'm fine with being a child.
I don't want to think that you could go unrewarded after paying a price.
There's a zeppelin coming down.
Brigadier General Mustang?
He's supposed to be with you, at the northern front.
That is an impostor.
He is in Central and is after the Führer's life.
It could be a rat.
This is an old house.
Just to be sure,
I'll go have a look.
You guys watch after my family.
But...
In case anything happens,
take them to the command center.
My family is more important to me than my life.
I knew you would come alone.
Is this the first time
you have betrayed my trust?
You're the one
who betrayed us first.
You mean my being a homunculus?
Whether or not you are human
is no great matter.
Then does it even matter?
Since I have become Führer, I have eliminated other races through recurring wars
and have continued to expand our territory.
But all of it was so that you could create a Philosopher's Stone.
Those who have been made desperate by war
seek the Philosopher's Stone.
People are fools.
And you have those foolish people
make Philosopher's Stones, do you?
And then we take the Philosopher's Stones from you, saving you from ruin.
You could say that
we are God's apostles.
There is no God!
That may be so.
However, there are devils:
you alchemists!
Too bad.
The explosive force of an open space
does not compare to that of a closed space.
Though I'm sure that the great Flame Alchemist
was already aware of that.
I can see air currents!
That's how I realized that
this cave had been closed up!
Very soon, you will become me.
Envy!
You can't let him use alchemy.
You dumbass!
Bring my... Bring my mama back to life!
Naughty boy.
Right now, the Philosopher's Stone
has been activated to its maximum level.
If you were to use alchemy here,
the transmutation would be started,
don't you know.
And here I let you live because
I thought you were still of use to me.
The gate...
It's still here!
Ed!
Brother!
Al?
I'm back...
So that's it.
That other "me" over there died.
I've used yet another life
from the other side, have I?
That was amazing, Edward-kun.
Doctor Marcoh?
Why are you here?
You know why, don't you?
Ed,
you're the one who turned Doctor Marcoh
over to the Führer, aren't you?
There's no way
he could be safe.
He's long since
gone into his stomach.
It's as though you were the one who killed him.
And while we're at it,
that goes for me too.
It must be difficult,
fighting the faces of those you know.
Even though you've convinced yourself
that it's not the real person!
Is that it?!
Is that the only power you've got?!
If so, I've got you beat!
I've already defeated
many other homunculi.
I even defeated the one
who looked like my mom.
At this point, no matter
whose face you take on...
That's it.
Kill me right.
See? Hard, isn't it?
Don't do that, Edward.
You've got no right
to order me around!
Makes no difference to me,
but there's no telling what will happen to your brother.
The Philosopher's Stone has been activated.
If a transmutation were to occur around him, then I'm sure...
...you know what will happen.
Don't get too full of yourself!
It's no use!
I'm stronger, after all!
Why, you!
Don't, Ed!
Stop messing with me!
Edward-kun!
Ed...
Fullmetal! Are you trying to kill me?!
That face is the easiest one
for me to hit!
Show me your real face!
Is using other people's faces
and taking advantage of others
the only thing you can do?!
You want to see it that badly?
Show it to me, if you can!
I'll show you!
What's the matter?
You wanted to see it, didn't you?
Dad?
Envy was the first homunculus,
created when Hohenheim was still young.
The boy that he had with me at the time
died from mercury poisoning.
He tried to bring him back to life somehow, but he failed.
And then he abandoned me.
You can understand...
why I hate him, right?
Brother?
Ed...
Ed!